Guide to the Jewish Community Council of Greater Washington records, 1937-1988 MS2012
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Committees, task torces, and working groups, 1941-1983; MS2012 Series 2; 22.5 Linear feet
  - Israel and the Middle East: Jerusalem Exhibit - Montgomery Mall, 1981 June 01-14 (Box 55, Folder 22)
  - Israel and the Middle East: American Israel Affairs Committee Memoranda, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 23)
  - Israel and the Middle East: American Jewish Committee Memoranda, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 24)
  - Israel and the Middle East: Anti-Defamation League, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 25)
  - Arbitration Committee Records, 1971-1972 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1949-1956 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1957-1958 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1959 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1960-1961 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1966-1967 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1976-1977 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Budget Committee Records, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Community Relations Committee Records, 1945-1955 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Constituent Services Committee Records, 1978-1979 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Constitution and By-Laws Committee Records, 1946-1958 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Constitution and By-Laws Committee Records, 1964-1973 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Constitution and By-Laws Committee Records, 1978-1979 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Emergency Mobilization Committee Records, 1976 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Energy Task Force Records, 1977 January-October (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Energy Task Force Records, 1977 November-December (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Energy Task Force Records, 1978 January-May (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Energy Task Force Records, 1978 June-December (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Energy Task Force Records, 1979-1980 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Evaluation Committee Records, 1977-1978 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Hanafi Review Committee Records (see also Subject Files: Hanafi Attack), 1977-1978 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Community Council Relocation of Offices Records, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Officers' Meeting Records, 1973-1977 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Officers' Meeting Records, 1978-1979 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - TV and Radio Committee Records - The Jewish Community Hour, 1975-1976 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - TV and Radio Committee Records - The Jewish Community Hour, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - TV and Radio Committee Records - The Jewish Community Hour, 1978-1979 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Youth Affairs Committee Records (fragmentary), 1973-1979 (Box 57, Folder 12)
- Other constituent organizations, 1945-1983; MS2012 Series 3; 6.5 Linear feet
  This series contains materials from various constituent organizations of the Jewish Community Council of Greater Washington which share the same mission and concerns. Groups include: Baltimore-Washington Union of Jewish Students, Jewish Youth Assembly, Prince George's County Jewish Alliance, National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council, United Jewish Federation of Greater Washington, Interfaith Social Action, Metropolitan Ecumenical Training Center (METC), and Metropolitan Washington Urban Coalition (MWUC). The bulk of materials in this series are agendas, memoranda, minutes, reports, news releases, newsletters, correspondence, pamphlets, handbills, bulletins, and newspaper clippings.
  - Doreinu ("Our Generation") Newspaper of the Baltimore Washington Union of Jewish Students, 1971-1974 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Baltimore-Washington Union of Jewish Students, 1975-1977 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Baltimore-Washington Union of Jewish Students, 1978-1979 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly Israel Fair, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Travel Fair, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly Orientation Retreat, 1972 October 14-15 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Salute to Israel Parade, 1973 May 13 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Salute to Israel Parade, 1973 May 13 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Youth Assembly, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly Orientation Retreat, 1974 September 08 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Youth Assembly, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Travel Fair, 1975 January 26 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Soviet Jewry Seminar, 1975 November 09 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Prisoners of Conscience Demonstration, 1975 November 16 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Youth Assembly, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Fair, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Hanukkah Torch Run, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly Israel Independence Day Celebration, 1976 May 04 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Youth Assembly, 1976 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1976 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Fair, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Matza Protest, 1977 March 28 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Hanukkah Torch Run, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Hanukkah Torch Run - Photos, 1977-1978 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Youth Assembly, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Directors Group, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Fair, 5 February, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Jewish Youth Assembly Leadership Institute, 1978 November 07 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Soviet Jewry Prisoner of Conscience Vigil, 1978 November 07 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Youth Assembly, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Fair, 1979 February 11 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly POC Vigil, 1979 November 15 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Hanukkah Torch Run, 1979 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Hanukkah Torch Run, 1979 (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Youth Assembly, 1979 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1979 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Fair, 1980 February 10 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly Soviet Jewry Tikkun, 1980 October 11 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly Prisoner of Conscience Vigil, 1980 November 12 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly Hanukuh Torch Run, 1980 December 07 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Hanukah Torch Run, 1981 December 20 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Youth Assembly, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Fair, 1981 February 08 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Youth Assembly, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Israel Fair, 1982 February 07 (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Youth Assembly, 1982 (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1982 (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Youth Assembly, 1983 (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Jewish Youth Assembly: Youth Director's Group, 1983 (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Memos, Minutes, Correspondence, 1975 January-April (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Memos, Minutes, Correspondence, 1975 May-December (Box 60, Folder 19)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Memos, Minutes, Correspondence, 1976 January-April (Box 60, Folder 20)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Memos, Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, 1976 May-December (Box 60, Folder 21)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Memos, Minutes, Correspondence, 1977 January-April (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Memos, Minutes, Correspondence, 1977 May-December (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Memos, Correspondence, Reports, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Memos, Correspondence, Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - "What's Happening in the P.G. County Jewish Community,", 1960 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County Public Schools - Controversy Over New Guidelines on Christmas Observance, 1972 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Jewish Community Council of Bowie, MD, 1970-1980 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Organization of the P.G. County Jewish Alliance, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Religious Holiday Observance in the Public School, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County School Calendar and Jewish Holiday Observance, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County Protest Over School Calendar Changes and Issue of Jewish Holiday Observance, September-December, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County Public Schools - Questionnaire on Religious Holiday Observance, 1975-1977 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Ethnic Heritage Studies - Neighborhoods Uniting Project, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County School Calendar Observance and Jewish Holiday Observance, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Bowie, MD Jews for Jesus Concert, October, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Religion in the Public Schools - Speech at Nevey Shalom, Bowie, 1977 November 02 (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - "Morals and Conduct" Amendment to P.G. County Code, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - Cross Burnings in P.G. County, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County School Calendar and Jewish Holiday Observance, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County School Athletic Programs and Observance of Religious Holidays, 1975-1977 (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County Committee - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1975-1977 (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - P.G. County Jewish Alliance - P.G. County Jewish Alliance Cooperation with Community Ministry of P.G. County, 1977-1979 (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC) Intercultural Education Committee, 1945-1947 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - NJCRAC Intercultural Education Committee, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - NJCRAC Committee on Work with Labor, Veterans, and other Special Groups, 1959 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Church/State and Interreligious Relationships - Memos, Minutes, 1964-1970 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - NJCRAC Bicentennial Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - NJCRAC Holocaust Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - NJCRAC Executive Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Church/State and Interreligious Relationships - Synagogue Council of America, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Church/State and Interreligious Relationships, 1972-1979 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Individual Freedom and Jewish Security, 1974-1979 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Equal Opportunity, 1978 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Equal Opportunity, 1979 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Equal Opportunity, 1981-1982 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1972-1973 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1974-1975 (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1976 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1977 January-April (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1977 May-September (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1977 October-December (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1978 January-March (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1978 April-December (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1979 January-April (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1979 May-December (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1980 January-April (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1980 May-December (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1981 January-July (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1981 August-December (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - NJCRAC Commission on International Community Relations Concerns, 1982 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1970 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1974-1975 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1976 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1977 January-March (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1977 April-June (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1977 July-September (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1977 October-December (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1978 January-March (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1978 April-August (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1978 September-December (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1979 January-June (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1979 July-August (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1979 September-October (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1979 November-December (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1980 January-February (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1980 March (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1980 April-May (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1980 June-July (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1980 August-September (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1980 October-December (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1981 January-March (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1981 April-May (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1981 June-December (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - NJCRAC Commission on Israel, 1982 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - NJCRAC 20th Anniversary Plenary Session Report, 1964 June (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - NJCRAC Plenary Session Draft Resolutions, 1965 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1970-1971 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1973-1974 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1974 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1975 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1976-1977 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1978-1979 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1979-1980 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - NJCRAC Joint Program Plan, 1980-1981 (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - NJCRAC - MacIver Report on Jewish Community Relations Agencies, 1951 May (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - NJCRAC - MacIver Report: Response, Correspondence, 1951 June-July (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - NJCRAC - MacIver Report: Response, Correspondence, 1951 August (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - NJCRAC - MacIver Report: Response, Correspondence, 1951 September-October (Box 65, Folder 19)
  - NJCRAC - MacIver Report: Response, Correspondence, 1951 November-December (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - NJCRAC - MacIver Report, 1952-1953 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - United Jewish Appeal Federation (UJAF) - Minutes, Correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - UJAF - Minutes Correspondence, 1978 January-April (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - UJAF - Memos, Reports, 1978 May-December (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - UJAF - Memos, Minutes, 1979 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - UJAF - Report of Task Force on Resettlement Program for Russian Jews, 1979 January 09 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - UJAF - Multiple Appeals Document, 1979-1980 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - UJAF - Outreach to Unaffiliated Teens, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Interfaith Committee of Greater Washington, 1974-1975 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Interfaith Committee of Greater Washington, 1976 January-September (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Interfaith Committee of Greater Washington, 1976 October-December (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Interfaith Committee of Greater Washington, 1977 January-March (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Interfaith Committee of Greater Washington, 1977 April-May (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Interfaith Committee of Greater Washington, 1977 June-December (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Interfaith Conference of Metropolitan Washington, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Interfaith Conference of Metropolitan Washington, 1979 January (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Interfaith Conference of Metropolitan Washington, 1979 February-April (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Interfaith Conference of Metropolitan Washington - Infant Mortality, 1979 May (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Interfaith Conference of Metropolitan Washington, 1979 May-June (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Interfaith Conference of Metropolitan Washington - Interfaith Musical Concert, 1980 November 24 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1978 January-February (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1978 March-April (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1978 May (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1978 June-July (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1978 August-September (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1978 October (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1978 November (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Interreligious Association of Greater Washington, 1978 December (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Interreligious Coalition and The DC Election Campaign, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1963 April-June (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1963 July-August (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1963 September-December (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1964 January-April (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1964 May-August (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1964 September-December (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1965 January-April (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1965 May (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1965 June-December (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Interreligious Committee on Race Relations, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Marchyland Interfaith Legislative Committee, 1978 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Marchyland Interfaith Legislative Committee, 1979 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Marchyland Interfaith Legislative Committee, 1979 (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Marchyland Interfaith Legislative Committee - Governor's Commission on Welfare Grants, 1979 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Marchyland Interfaith Legislative Committee, 1980 (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Metropolitan Ecumenical Training Center (METC), 1969 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - METC, 1970 January-March (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - METC, 1970 April-December (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - METC, 1973-1975 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - METC, 1976 January-September (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - METC, 1976 October-December (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - METC, 1977 January-February (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - METC - Pilgrimage to Jerusalem, 1977 February (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - METC, 1977 March-April (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - METC, 1977 May (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - METC, 1977 June-August (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - METC, 1977 September-December (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - METC, National Ministers March Around the White House for Jobs and Housing, 1975 January 15 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - METC, Protestant-Jewish-Catholic (ProJeCt), 1972 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - METC, ProJeCt, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - METC, ProJeCt - Deborah's Place, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - METC, ProJeCt, 1974 (Box 69, Folder 17)
  - METC, ProJeCt, 1975-1976 (Box 69, Folder 18)
  - Metropolitan Washington Urban Coalition (MWUC), 1967 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - MWUC, 1968 January (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - MWUC, 1968 February (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - MWUC, 1968 March (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - MWUC, 1968 April (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - MWUC, 1968 May (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - MWUC, 1968 June-September (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - MWUC, 1968 October (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - MWUC, 1968 November (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - MWUC, 1968 November (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - MWUC, 1969 January-February (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - MWUC, 1969 March-April (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - MWUC, 1969 May (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - MWUC, 1969 June (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - MWUC, 1969 August-December (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - MWUC, 1970 January-September (Box 70, Folder 16)
  - MWUC, 1970-1971 (Box 70, Folder 17)
- Subject files, 1937-1988; MS2012 Series 4; 11 Linear feet
  This series contains a diverse range of subject files with materials including memoranda, correspondence, reports, booklets, clippings, minutes, handbills, and excerpts from the Congressional Record. There is also an audio cassette. Some folders contain items in Hebrew, German, and French.
  This content of this series reflects the variety of issues the Council has addressed. For instance, it contains information on African American/Jewish relations from the civil rights era and the urban crisis of 1960's, including the Council's efforts to work with black leaders such as Martin Luther King, Jr. in dealing with fundamental problems facing minorities. The relationship of Jews and Catholics is also covered in this series, especially the implications of the Vatican II Ecumenical Council in 1964, which called for the exchange of mutual knowledge and brotherly dialogue between Christians and Jews. Other subjects of interest include files regarding humane slaughtering legislation from the 1940's to 1960's as it affected the Jewish practice of shechita, as well as a proposed national Jewish population survey in the mid-1960's.
  The following presidents of the Jewish Community Council of Greater Washington are also represented in the subject files: Solomon Metz (1938-1943); Hymen Goldman (1943-1949); Isadore Breslau (1949-1953); Aaaron Goldman (1953-1957); Albert Arent (1957-1961); Joel Wolfson (1961); Richard Lyon (1961-1965); Louis Grossberg (1965-1969); and Seymour Wolf (1969-1972).
  - America Salutes Israel Celebration, April, 1956 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - American Academic Association for Peace in the Middle East, 1978 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - American Association for Jewish Education, 1960-1964 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - American Association for Jewish Education - Articles on Jewish Education, 1965 (Box 71, Folder 4)